다이간다는 방을 밝게 하고 적당히 떨어져서 봐!
Watch Daigunder in a bright room and keep some distance!
Смотри Дайгандера со включённым светом, сидя подальше от экрана!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
Дайгандер!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе,
마음의 눈을 열어라
Open your eyes of soul
Распахни шире око души
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
(Bakutou Sengen Daigunder)
Боевой претендент Дайгандер!
뜨거운 마음을 담아
With all your hot heart
Пусть меня охватит твой жар сердца,
오늘도 기적을 맹새해
I will make a miracle today too
Чтобы сотворить сумел я чудо
드래곤 소드 작렬이야
Dragon Sword bursts
Вспыхнет ярким светом Меч Дракона!
싸워야 할 라이벌은
The rival I have to fight against is
Побороть я должен свой упавший дух,
좌절하려는 내 자신
right here, dispirited myself
что пути к успеху преграждает мне,
어제보다도 진화해서
Evolve even more than yesterday
Вырасти сегодня больше, чем вчера
강해져라!
And become strong!
И сильнее стать!
다다다다 다 다 다 다다
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
Пушка Дракона!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе
에너지 전개로
Open up all your energy and
Дай энергии выход, сказав...
다다다다다다 다
Dadadadadada da
Дададададада-да!!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
쓰러트려라 타도해라
Defeat and knock down
Победи и врагов одолей
빛나는 강철의
Fighter of shining steel
Сталью сверкает тело твоё,
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
제 25 화
The 25th Episode
Эпизод 25
발각선언!
Revelation Declaration!
빅뱅의 정체!!
The True Identity of Big Bang!!
(en: Maelstrom's Madness)
온다!
Incoming!
가자, 트라이혼!
Let's do this, Trihorn!
사이드에서의 공격에 대하는 반응이 늦다!
Your reaction to the attacks from side is slow!
스펙터 슬래시!
Spector Slash!
본렉스하고 쟤들 힘내고 있네.
Bonerex's team is really doing their best!
서봇, 그 배선 코드는 아까 회로에 연결해.
Supbot, connect that cord to the circuit I told you before.
어서 해모그!
Hurry up-mogu!
그래, 어서 해! 다이노 유닛은 트레이닝으로 실력을 올리고 있는데!
Yeah, hurry up! Dino Unit is improving themselves by training, and look at  us!
그래, 그 녀석들에게 늦을 수는 없지.
Yes, we cannot fall behind them.
멋대로인 소리 마. 완벽한 배틀은 완벽한 메인터넌스에서 온다고들 하잖아.
Don't be unreasonable. A perfect battle could be done only with a perfect maintenance.
그거 누가 한 말이야?
Who said that?
물론 나.
Of course, me.
이야, 하루카도 가끔은 옳은 소리 하네!
Hey, you're sometimes right too, Haruka!
가끔이라니!
I'm always right!
애니멀 유닛이 끝나면 다음은 류구하고 건더야.
When it's done for Animal Unit, it's Ryugu and Gunder's turn.
어? 난 괜찮아!
What?! I'm perfectly fine!
봐! 보는 대로 원기발랄이니까!
Look! I'm full of energy as you see!
정말... 어디 이상해져도 모른다.
Really... I don't know even if you get weird.
어이어이, 우릴 속일 생각이라면 틀렸어!
Hey, hey, if you're trying to fool us, then you failed!
잠깐. 다들 이상해.
Wait. Everyone looks strange.
다들 왜 그래?
What's wrong, everyone?
서봇!
Supbot!
통신 기능 이상?
Problem in communication functions?
이, 이건!
W- what's this?!
특수한 에너지파가 송신되고 있어!
A strange energy wave is being transmitted!
정신 차려, 류구!
Hang on there, Ryugu!
건더!
Gunder!
류, 류구! 괜찮아?
R- Ryugu! Are you alright?
에너지파가 사라졌어.
That energy wave has disappeared.
그런 거 같아.
Seems so.
그건 그렇고, 저 흐린 영상은 대체...
Anyway, what was that blurred video?
그보다, 본렉스 얘들은?
What about Bonerex and others?
음, 오버홀이 필요한 거 같아.
It seems that they need an overhaul.
이, 이 정도쯤이야...
T- this is nothing...
그래.
Right.
됐으니까 무리하지 마!
Just keep it easy!
그래그래! 무리하면 안 돼모그!
Yeah, yeah! Don't try to overdo it-mogu!
상당히 강력한 에너지파였어.
It was quite a powerful energy wave.
그래도 우린 그만큼의 피해는 없었잖아.
But we didn't receive that much damage.
다이노 유닛은 어째서...
Why were Dino Unit damaged so much?
그 때 트레이닝 때는 돔에 지붕이 열려 있었으니까.
During their training, the roof of dome was open.
우리는 다이베이스의 벽 덕분에 살았다는 거구나.
So we've been protected by Daibase's walls.
그래.
Right.
그거 빅뱅의 공격이었어?
Was that Big Bang's attack?
글쎄, 영상의 메시지를 보내려고 했으니까 그건 아닐 거 같은데...
Well, I don't think so, as they tried to send some kind of message...
그럴 리가. 저 힘으로 메시지를?
No way. A message, with that power?!
다들 잘 살고 있냐!
Are you all living well?
난 언제라도 좋다!
I'm always doing so!
-할아버지!
-박사님!
-Grandpa!
-Professor!
갑자기 뭐야?
What's up, so suddenly?
기뻐해라! 난 결국 드라고버스트가 어디 있는지 알아냈다!
Be happy! I finally found out where Dragoburst is!
-어?
-드라고버스트가 있는 곳을?
-Really?
-Where Dragoburst is?!
그래. 지금 그 곳에 가려고 준비하던 참이다!
Yeah. I was preparing to go to that place!
우리도 같이 갈래!
We'll go together!
거기서 기다려!
Wait for us there!
상대는 드라고버스트야.
We're facing Dragoburst.
그러니까 간다는 거야!
That's why we're going!
좋다! 그럼 이 장소의 정보를 보낼게.
Great! Then I'll let you know where I am.
박사님, 드라고버스트는 어디에 있나요?
Professor, where is Dragoburst?
그건...
That's...
응, 응!
Yeah, yeah!
뭐야, 니들?!
What are you guys doing?!
타이거마루에 로우가마루!
Tigermaru and Rougamaru!
오래 기다리셨다. 아, 우리의 차례요!
We've been waiting for along time! ah, it's finally our turn!
숨는 것에는 자신이 있소!
We're confident that we're good at hiding-gozaru!
이 자식들!
You bastards!
아, 미안하지만 쇼타임은
ah, sorry to inform you that the show time...
이걸로 끝이오!
...is over-gozaru!
-할아버지!
-박사님!
-Grandpa!
-Professor!
어서 구하러 가자!
Let's go to rescue him right now!
그래!
Right!
잠깐만. 어디 있는지 모르는데...
Wait. We don't know where he is.
가까이라도 가고 보자!
Let's go nearby for now!
서봇, 다이노 유닛은 잘 부탁해!
Supbot, take good care of Dino Unit!
아키라야말로 박사님을 부탁해!
Akira, you take good care of the professor!
맡겨 둬!
Leave it to me!
자, 이제 눈을 떠도 좋소.
Now you may open your eyes-gozaru!
여, 여긴...
T- this place...
왜 날 여기에 데려왔냐?!
Why did you take me to here?!
임마, 꺼내라! 날 여기서 어쩔 생각이냐!
Hey, get me out of here! What are you going to do with me?!
외치지 마쇼! 떠들지 마쇼! 날뛰지 마쇼!
Don't yell! Don't talk! Don't rage!
아, 네 운명은...
ah, your destiny will be...
-여기!
-프로페서 빅뱅이 전부 쥐고 있소.
-Here!
-decided by Professor Big Bang-gozaru.
프로페서 빅뱅? 그 자는 대체 뭘 위해 이런 짓을 하는가.
Professor Big Bang? Why is that guy doing this?
설마...
Could it be...
-안달 마쇼! 잠깐
-여기서 가만히 기다리고 있으시오!
-Don't be impatient! For now
-keep silent and wait here-gozaru!
그럴 필요는 없다.
That won't be necessary.
긴잔!
Ginzan!
긴잔, 아, 여긴 왜 왔슈?
Ginzan, ah, why are you here?
박사를 놓아 줘라.
Let the professor go.
-뭐?!
-빅뱅의 명령에 거역할 심산이오?
-What?!
-Are you going to disobey Big Bang-gozaru?
인질을 잡는 비겁한 짓을 하도록 가만히 두지 않는다.
I shall not forgive cowardly acts like taking hostages.
오, 해 볼 셈이오?
Oh, are you up for a fight-gozaru?
그렇다면, 아, 처벌해 주겠소!
If then, ah, we'll punish you!
트윈 리볼버!
Twin Revolver!
밀리겠구려!
We're gonna be pushed!
-분하고
-아, 원통하구려...
-What a
-ah, deep regret...
분한... 거 같소...
Regret... we sure do-gozaru...
흥.
Hmph.
긴잔, 너...
Ginzan, you...
어? 말도 안 돼!
What?! No way!
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
하지메 박사님의 위치를 담은 정보를 수신했어.
We got a data about where Prof. Hajime is.
-어?
-박사님이 보냈어?
-Really?
-Did the professor send that?
그게, 긴잔이 보낸 거 같아.
It seems that Ginzan sent it.
-뭐?
-왜 긴잔이!
-What?
-Why would Ginzan do that?
어쩔래? 함정일지도 모르는데.
What are you gonna do? It might be a trap.
-그래도 그곳에 갈 수밖에 없어.
-그래.
-But we just have to go.
-Right.
왜냐, 긴잔.
Why would you do this, Ginzan?
나는 다이간다하고 정정당당히 승부하고 싶을 뿐이다. 이런 방식은 마음에 안 든다.
I just want to fight Daigunder fair and square. I do not like this kind of way of doing things.
그렇지만 이러면 네게는...
But if you do this, what about you?
난 내가 하고 싶은 대로 할 뿐이다.
I just do what I want to do.
너 답구나.
It's just like you.
뭐, 뭐야?!
W- what's this?!
뭐?!
What?!
긴잔!
Ginzan!
환영한다, 하지메 박사.
Welcome, Prof. Hajime.
네가 프로페서 빅뱅이냐!
You must be that Professor Big Bang!
-여기야.
-여긴 전에 할아버지가 말한 연구소!
-Here we are.
-This is the lab that my grandpa told us about before!
그래. 드라고버스트가 파괴한 연구소임이 틀림없다.
Right. This is the lab that Dragoburst destroyed.
그래도 이런 곳에 왜...
But why this place?
뭔가 이상해! 사람은 없는데 연구소의 동력이 살아 있어!
Something's not right! There are no people here, but the power is alive!
동력이?
Power's alive?
이 아래에 꽤 큰 공간이 있는 거 같아모그!
It seems that there's some large space below here-mogu!
아래?
Below?
-그렇구나!
-지하실이야!
-I see!
-The basement!
날 어쩔 셈이냐?
What are you going to do with me?
거역하지 않으면 이 이상 상처는 안 입히겠다.
If you don't disobey me, I won't damage you more.
흥! 날 협박할 셈이냐. 안됐지만 네놈의 방식은 마음에 안 든다!
Hmph! Are you making a threat to me? Too bad, because I don't like your way of doing things!
그만해라, 빅뱅!
Stop it, Big Bang!
긴잔!
Ginzan!
그럼 하지메 박사. 네게 묻고 싶은 게 있다.
Then, Prof. Hajime, I want to ask you something.
드라고버스트가 어디 있는지 아는 것 같구나.
It seems that you know where Dragoburst is.
말해라. 어디냐.
Tell me. Where is him?
왜냐! 왜 네가 드라고버스트를!
Why! Why do you know Dragoburst?!
알고 싶나?
Do you want to know?
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
이 소리는, 아, 비상 경보!
This sound must be, ah, emergency alarm!
침입자이오!
An invader-gozaru!
-여기부터는
-아, 통행금지!
-From this point,
-ah, you're not allowed!
-타이거마루에 로우가마루!
-역시 박사님은 여기 있구나.
-Tigermaru and Rougamaru!
-Then the professor really is here.
좋다! 여긴 우리가 처리하겠어!
Well then! We'll deal with this here!
파이터 체인지!
Fighter Change!
아, 건방지오!
ah, how impudent!
반사해 주겠소!
You'll take that back-gozaru!
파이어 애로!
Fire Arrow!
클래시 뱅!
Clash Bang!
라이징 클로!
Rising Claw!
타이거 타츠마키기리!
Tiger Tatsumakigiri!
로우가 미카즈키기리!
Rouga Mikazukigiri!
-지금이야! 가자!
-그래!
-Now! Let's go!
-Right!
네이놈!
How dare you!
어딜!
Nope!
-우릴 얕잡아보면
-안되지모그!
-Don't look down
-of us-mogu!
흥, 지금 와서 말할 필요도 없지만. 이 사회는 정치, 경제, 산업 등 여러 분야에서 로봇이 필수불가결한 존재이다.
Hmph. It's obvious that the robots are necessary in this society in politics, economics, and various industries.
그 로봇을 진화시키는 최고의 실험장이야말로 배틀 로봇 세계.
The best testing grounds of evolving those robots are the world of battle robots.
그렇다면 배틀 로봇을 제패하는 자야말로 인간 사회를 제패하는 자가 된다.
That means, who rules over the battle robots will become the ruler of the human society.
알고 있겠지. 세계에서 제일 강한 배틀 로봇의 증표. 배틀 로봇 사회에 군림하면 결국엔 이 세계를 지배한다.
You already know. With the strongest battle robot, I'll reign over the battle robot society and rule over the world.
그걸 위해서는 드라고버스트의 힘이 필요하다.
And for that, I need Dragoburst's power.
내 동지가 되어라, 하지메 박사.
Become my comrade, Prof. Hajime.
거절한다.
I refuse!
배틀 로봇의 힘만을 이용하려 하는 너하고 함께할 수는 없다!
I will not join you, when you're just trying to use battle robots' powers!
-할아버지!
-박사님!
-Grandpa!
-Professor!
왔구나!
You've came!
흥, 왔구나.
Hmph. You're here.
멍청한 놈들.
Fools.
너는!
You must be...!
흥, 나야말로 프로페서 빅뱅!
Hmph! I am Professor Big Bang!
-네가
-빅뱅!
-So you're
-Big Bang!
비겁해! 갑자기!
That's cowardly! All of the sudden!
어? 긴잔!
Huh? Ginzan!
빅뱅! 너라는 놈은!
Big Bang! What kind of guy are you?!
안됐군, 하지메 박사. 우리가 손을 잡으면 배틀 로봇 개발에서 우리하고 견줄 사람은 없을 텐데.
Too bad, Prof. Hajime. If we work together, nobody will be able to develop a better battle robot than ours.
전에 동료였을 때처럼이냐!
Just like when we were working together back then!
뭐?!
What?!
흥.
Hmph.
역시군. 빅뱅이라는 건 너 말이였군!
Just as I thought. That Big Bang was you!
다이쿤 교수!
Prof. Daikun!
다이쿤! 오래 전에 버린 이름이다. 지금의 나는!
Daikun! That is the name I threw away long time ago. I of now am...!
프로페서 빅뱅!
Professor Big Bang!
오랜만입니다, 하지메 박사님.
It's been a while, Prof. Hajime.
저 놈이라는 느낌이 들었더니.
I did think it was him.
긴잔. 타이거마루. 로우가마루가 가진 시스템.
Ginzan, Tigermaru, and Rougamaru's system.
전부 내가 만든 배틀 로봇하고 닮아 있었으니!
All of them were similar to the battle robots I made!
그럼 할아버지가 전에 말한 드라고버스트의 또 하나의 개발자가!
Then the another developer of Dragoburst that my grandpa told about must be...
들었구나.
You know it well.
그 때 우리는 가진 모든 힘을 써서 드라고버스트를 개발했다.
Back then, we did everything we could to develop Dragoburst.
그게... 완성된 놈들이...
But they... the completed ones...
그리고 지금, 놈들이 태어난 이 인연의 장소에서 이 친부모가 재회했단 것이다.
And at a place where they were born, the parents have met again.
그 이후로 난 계속 드라고버스트를 찾고 있었다. 왜 그 때 그런 짓을 했는가.
Ever since, I was looking for Dragoburst, wondering why did he do that.
이유 따위는 필요 없다! 내가 원하는 건 놈의 힘 뿐이다.
I'm not interested in reasons! What I want is his power.
힘?
Power?
힘이야말로 모든 것이다. 이 프로페서 빅뱅이 세계를 지배하기 위해서는 배틀 로봇의 힘만이 필요할 뿐이다!
Power is everything. In order for me, Professor Big Bang to rule over the world, I need battle robots' powers!
틀렸어!
You're wrong!
배틀 로봇은 그런 걸 위해 있는 게 아니야!
Battle robots do not exist for that purpose!
맞아!
He's right!
무식하긴. 배틀 로봇은 결국 인간에 의해 움직이는 꼭두각시 인형.
How foolish. Battle robots are nothing more than puppets operated by humans.
나같이 우수한 지도자가 쓰는 도구일 뿐이다!
They're nothing more than simple tools for an excellent leader like me!
도, 도구라고?!
T- tools?!
아니야, 아니야! 배틀 로봇은 인간하고 같은 동료잖아!
No, you're totally wrong! Battle robots are simply friends of humans!
누가 위고 아래고 그런 건 없을 테야!
There's no superiority between them!
맞아! 우리는 서로 도우며 살아갈 뿐이야!
Yeah! We just live by helping each other!
빅뱅. 아니, 다이쿤 교수! 나도 이제 알겠다!
Big Bang, no, Prof. Daikun! I finally understand!
드라고버스트가 왜 그 연구소를 파괴하고 사라졌는가!
I understand why did Dragoburst destroy the lab and disappeared!
흥. 이 이상 이야기해도 소용없군.
Hmph. I see talking with you won't do a thing.
뭐, 뭔 짓이냐!
W- what are you trying to do?!
드라고버스트가 어디 있는지 알아내기 위함이지.
To find out where Dragoburst is.
네 뇌로 직접.
Directly from your brain.
하지 마!
Don't!
늦었구나!
Sorry for being late!
-브라이온!
-이글 애로!
-드리모그!
-Bullion!
-Eagle Arrow!
-Drimog!
윙 커터!
Wing Cutter!
빅뱅!
Big Bang!
용서할 수 없어!
Totally unforgivable!
-아, 여긴 위험하오!
-일단 퇴각이오!
-ah, it's dangerous here!
-Retreat for now-gozaru!
다시 보자, 제군!
See you again, gentlemen!
트윈 리볼버!
Twin Revolver!
류구! 건더! 헤드합체!
Ryugu! Gunder! Head Fusion!
폭투왕 다이간다!
Wild Fight King Daigunder!
다이간다! 드래곤 소드야!
Daigunder! Use Dragon Sword!
썬더 클로!
Thunder Claw!
안 되겠어! 끝이 없네!
It's not working! There's no end to this!
그 동안 서둘러서 촉수의 제어 시스템을 찾아라!
Meanwhile, hurry up and find the control system of those tentacles!
네.
Got it.
저기! 아키라, 저 문 왼쪽에 있는 벽이야!
Akira! In the wall next to that door!
이글 애로!
Eagle Arrow!
파이어 애로!
Fire Arrow!
저거야!
That's it!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
공격!
Attack!
드래곤 캐논이 안 먹혀!
Dragon Cannon isn't working!
쳇.
Tch.
그런!
No way!
아키라! 날 써라!
Akira! Use me!
드래곤 리볼버다!
Use Dragon Revolver!
긴잔!
Ginzan!
촉수는 우리에게 맡겨라!
Leave the tentacles to us!
좋아! 다이간다, 긴잔하고 합체해!
Alright! Daigunder, combine with Ginzan!
지금이다!
Now!
드래곤 리볼버!
Dragon Revolver!
다이간다! 다음에 볼 때는 그 때야말로 끝장을 낼 때다!
Daigunder! When we meet again, that's time to finish our business!
할아버지...
Grandpa...
어쩔 수 없지. 일단 다이랜드에 돌아가자.
It couldn't be helped. Let's go back to Dailand for now.
본렉스! 이제 괜찮아?
Bonerex! Are you alright now?
그래. 걱정을 끼쳤구나.
Yes. Sorry for making you worry.
언제라도 배틀 가능해!
We can do battles right away!
아!
Look!
아까 특수 에너지파 분석이 끝났어!
The analysis for the strange energy wave is now complete!
에너지파?
Energy wave?
응응. 할아버지가 연락하기 전에 어딘가에서 모두한테 보내졌어.
Yeah! Before you contacted us, someone sent to everybody!
텔레파시같이 삐비빅하고!
Just like telepathy!
해석 결과 확인은 가능하나?
Can we check out the analysis result?
그래. 모니터에 보일게.
Yeah. I'll show it on the display.
이, 이건...
T- that's...
다이간다와 드라고버스트이 합체다.
It's a fusion between Daigunder and Dragoburst.
-어?
-그래도 드라고버스트를 만든 건 오래 전이잖아?
-Huh?
-But isn't it been a while since you developed Dragoburst?
드라고버스트는 모든 개발을 담은 최신형의 합체 시스템을 채용했으니까 말이다.
Dragoburst adopted the newest merge systems containing all the development results.
다이간다의 기반이 된 시스템이니까.
His system is the foundation of Daigunder's system.
그럼 이 영상을 보낸 건...
Then the one who sent this video must be...
드라고버스트다.
It's Dragoburst.
그 말은...
That means...
그래. 이건 놈들의 도전장이야!
Yes, this is a challenge from them!
그럼 받아줄 수밖에 없지!
Then we have to accept it!
할아버지, 드라고버스트는 어디 있어?
Grandpa, where is Dragoburst?
우주다.
In the Space.
좋아! 다들 가자! 우주에!
Alright! Everyone, let's go to the Space!
끝없는 꿈을 꾸고 있어
Dreaming an endless dream
Я сон бесконечный вижу опять перед собой
몇번이고 쓰러져도
I fall down over and over again
Как упал, и лечу вниз вновь и вновь.
저 구름 위에는 분명히
Up over those clouds
Там, где-то в высотах, за чертой облаков
푸른 하늘이 펼쳐져 있을 거야
a blue sky awaits
голубое небо ждёт меня!
강해지기 위해서라면 누구도 혼자서는
To be strong, nobody can ever become
Сильным быть, чтоб никто превзойти не смог
강해지고 뜨거워질 수 없어
strong and hot, by oneself
Стать сильней, горячей, сам я хочу!
불꽃의 Fight Fight Fighting soul
Flaming fightin' fightin' fighting soul
Так гори, душа, душа бойца!
용기를 마주치는 그 때
When you face your courage
Смелость повстречай, и пусть ведёт она тебя в жизни.
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
느껴져 바로 너라는 게
I can feel it, yes, it's you
Я это чувствую, да, это ты!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
둘은 서로의 영웅
The two are heroes of each other
Два героя - части одного, нерушимы связи,
질 수 없는 같은 내일을
They run towards to the same tomorrow
Вместе в новый день по одной тропе спешат
바라보고 달려
that they cannot lose
И не собьются с неё!
다이간다가 드라고버스트에게 조종되어 합체당하고 말했어!
Dragoburst controlled Daigunder and forced him to combine!
결국 우리 앞에 모습을 드러낸 전설의 폭투신 드래곤 다이간다!
The one to finally show himself to us is Legendary Wild Fight God Dragon Daigunder!
그 압도적인 힘에 우리는 큰 위기에 처했어!
We're in a big trouble in front of that overwhelming power!
그래도 난 믿어! 친구를! 다이간다를! 승리를!
But still I believe in my friend! In Daigunder! In victory!
무한한 클러스터 파워 전개야!
Activate the infinite Cluster Power!
폭투선언 다이간다의 다음 이야기!
진상선언! 대우주의 대결투!!
Next time on Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
Truth Declaration! A Great Dual in the Great Space!!